Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA) Records
Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA) Records
- Organizational files
  - Project files
    - Carey Study
      - Final report, 1959 (Box 43)
      - Questionnaires, 1958
        - A-Co, 5 folders (Box 44)
        - D-O, 5 folders (Box 45)
        - P-V, 6 folders (Box 46)
        - W-Z, miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 47)
    - Center for Higher Continuing Education, proposal, 1967 (Box 47)
    - CSLEA
      - Ability and achievement of evening college and extension students, ca., 1958 (Box 47)
      - Affiliation contacts, 1963 (Box 47)
      - Affiliation possibilities with Syracuse University and Boston University, 1963 (Box 47)
      - Analysis of Center activities to implement policy, ca., 1959 (Box 47)
      - Audience Education Project, report, 1966 (Box 47)
      - Basic foundation proposal
        - 1963 (Box 47)
        - 1964 (Box 47)
        - Supporting material, undated (Box 47)
      - Clearinghouse, 1953-1960 (Box 48)
      - Committee on Bibliographic Services in Adult Education, 1960 (Box 48)
      - Community education programs, ca., 1961 (Box 48)
      - The community problem, 1955 (Box 48)
      - Conference on Evening College Adult Education, proposal, 1956 (Box 48)
      - Continuing Education Almanac, undated (Box 48)
      - Cooperative research project, proposal, 1961 (Box 48)
      - Core operation procedures, 1960 (Box 48)
      - CSLEA-NSA Joint Committee, 1956 (Box 48)
      - Discussion Leader Training Project, 1954 (Box 48)
      - Evaluation Project, 1961 (Box 48)
      - Evening college recruitment, proposal, 1960 (Box 48)
      - Faculty newsletter, ca., 1960 (Box 48)
      - Ford Foundation urban research, education, and extension grants, 1962 (Box 48)
      - Foundation contacts, 1962 (Box 48)
      - Future Center directions, recommendations, 1958 (Box 48)
      - "Future Directions of CSLEA,", 1960
        - Volume 1 (Box 48)
        - Volume 2 (Box 48)
        - Resume of field questionnaire (Box 48)
      - History of the CSLEA, by J. Whipple, draft, 1968 (Box 48)
      - Image of the CSLEA, 1966 (Box 48)
      - Institute in Liberal Studies, proposal, 1958 (Box 49)
      - Institute in Liberal Studies for University Administrators, 1957 (Box 49)
      - Inter-American Adult Education Project, 1961-1963 (Box 49)
      - Kenwood Cultural and Art Center, proposal, ca., 1958 (Box 49)
      - Lake Wilderness Liberal Arts Seminar for Community Leaders, 1958 (Box 49)
      - Liberal arts program in the evening college, study, 1952 (Box 49)
      - Liberal arts seminars, 1958 (Box 49)
      - Long-range research plans, 1959 (Box 49)
      - Membership rosters and mailing lists
        - 1964-1968 (Box 49)
        - 1956-1963 (Box 49)
      - Metro-Urban Education Conference, proposal, 1966 (Box 49)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities, staff discussion notes, 1967 (Box 49)
      - National policy statement on adult education in the United States, 1957 (Box 49)
      - National Seminar on University Urban Programs, proposal, 1962-1963 (Box 49)
      - New program for administration, outline, undated (Box 49)
      - Oxford Conference on Adult Education and Race Relations, 1966 (Box 49)
      - Participation in adult education programs, questionnaire, undated (Box 49)
      - Planning Conference on the Future of the Center, 1954 (Box 49)
      - Policy on credit and non-credit programs, 1957 (Box 49)
      - Policy on grants, 1958-1961 (Box 49)
      - Pre-retirement education program, ca. 1966 (Box 49)
      - Program goals, ca. 1963 (Box 49)
      - Programmed learning and adult education, memorandum, 1962 (Box 49)
      - Project for strengthening associations in higher education, ca., 1956 (Box 49)
      - Project "Teacher behavior, classroom social structure, student personality, and learning,", 1961-1963 (Box 49)
      - Projects of the Center, 1956 (Box 49)
      - "Projected programs during 1963-1970", 1962 (Box 49)
      - Proposal to the Carnegie Foundation, 1964 (Box 49)
      - Proposals to the Fund for Adult Education
        - Basic support of the Center
          - 1951-1952 (Box 49)
          - 1954-1958 (Box 49)
          - 1959-1960 (Box 50)
          - 1960-1961 (Box 50)
        - Internship program at the Center, undated (Box 50)
        - Introduction of an adult liberal arts degree into the evening college movement, 1953 (Box 50)
      - Proposal to the Inland Steel Foundation, 1963 (Box 50)
      - Proposal to the Inland Steel-Ryerson Foundation, 1963 (Box 50)
      - Proposals to the Johnson Foundation, 1965 (Box 50)
      - Proposals to the Kellogg Foundation, 1960-1963 (Box 50)
      - Proposal to U.S. Steel and other foundations, 1963 (Box 50)
      - Proposal to U.S. Steel Foundation, 1964 (Box 50)
      - Ranking of Center activities, undated (Box 50)
      - Recommendations to FAE on internships, scholarships, and fellowships, ca. 1952 (Box 50)
      - Relationships with associations in higher education, 1963 (Box 50)
      - Reports on current projects, 1959 (Box 50)
      - Research and development center, ca. 1967 (Box 50)
      - Research resources, undated (Box 50)
      - Resident labor education program brochure draft, 1964 (Box 50)
      - Results and accomplishments, 1963 (Box 50)
      - Special staff-board committee, 1960 (Box 50)
      - Status study of evening college and extension operations, 1959 (Box 50)
      - Subcommittee on Community Development Projects, report, 1956 (Box 50)
      - Survey of student opinion of teaching extension classes, 1958 (Box 50)
      - Unresolved problems in adult degree programs, report, ca., 1963 (Box 50)
      - Visiting staff member programs, report, 1960 (Box 50)
      - Visits with AUEC-NUEA affiliates, 1957-1964 (Box 50)
    - Child psychology textbook, report, 1957 (Box 51)
    - Cleveland College, 1956-1960 (Box 51)
    - Cleveland State University, recommendations for continuing education program, 1966 (Box 51)
    - Committee on Effective Teaching, 1960-1961 (Box 51)
    - Committee on Future Directions in Higher Adult Education, 1959 (Box 51)
    - Comparative adult education, proposal for a summer institute, 1965 (Box 51)
    - Conference on Newer Opportunities in College-Level Adult Education, 1955 (Box 51)
    - Conference on Special Degree Programs for Adults, 1964-1965 (Box 51)
    - Continuing Committee on Urban Affairs, 1961-1963 (Box 51)
    - Continuing education for the ministry, proposal for a center, 1965-1967 (Box 51)
    - Continuing education of the clergy, proposal for an institute, 1965-1967 (Box 51)
    - Correspondence education research project, 1965 (Box 51)
    - Correspondence Study Workshop, 1960 (Box 51)
    - Council on College-Level Examinations, ca. 1966 (Box 51)
    - Deans' and Directors' Institute on Liberal Studies, 1966 (Box 51)
    - Degree programs especially for adults, meeting, 1963 (Box 51)
    - Discussion Leader Project, 1954-1955 (Box 51)
    - Drake University, survey of evening college deans and directors, 1955 (Box 51)
    - Drexel Institute of Technology, interviews, 1954 (Box 51)
    - Ecumenical Institute of Religious Studies, description, undated (Box 51)
    - Education of counselors of adults, proposal, 1964 (Box 51)
    - Educational implications of the language arts, proposal for a summer institute, 1952 (Box 51)
    - ESSO Education Foundation, proposal for a grant to CSLEA, 1964 (Box 51)
    - Evaluation Project
      - Annual reports, 1961 (Box 51)
      - Community affairs area, 1960 (Box 52)
      - General, 1957-1961 (Box 52)
      - Illustrative evaluation devices, 1958 (Box 52)
      - Interim report, 1958 (Box 52)
      - Moral and ethical area, 1960 (Box 52)
      - Political and social area, 1960 (Box 52)
      - Report on present status and future plans for the project, 1961 (Box 52)
      - Report on the relevance to development of area examinations for special degree programs, 1961 (Box 52)
      - Summary of developments, 1960 (Box 52)
      - Summary report of progress, 1959 (Box 52)
    - "Experience for Living," memorandum on research and development project, 1966 (Box 52)
    - Experimental liberal arts curriculum materials for adults, evaluation, 1952 (Box 52)
    - Faculty grant program, ca. 1955-1957 (Box 52)
    - The Faculty Member in Adult Education, 1955 (Box 52)
    - Family Relations Program, New Haven County Extension Service, 1966-1967 (Box 52)
    - First International Conference on Comparative Adult Education, report, 1966 (Box 52)
    - Future directions in higher adult education, 1959-1963 (Box 52)
    - Girl guides and girl scouts, reports and various papers, 1960-1968 (Box 52)
    - Gould House Conference, Seminar on Liberal Education for Management, 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Great Plains Conference on Liberal Education for Adults, 1961 (Box 53)
    - Harvard University, survey form, 1962 (Box 53)
    - Higher adult education trends and directions, CSLEA statement, ca., 1965 (Box 53)
    - Higher Adult Education and the Emerging City Conference, summary, 1963-1964 (Box 53)
    - Higher adult education in Ohio
      - Report, 1964 (Box 53)
      - Working papers, 1963-1964 (Box 53)
    - Higher Education Act of 1965
      - Analysis, 1965-1966 (Box 53)
      - Projects, 1965 (Box 53)
    - Higher education for cultural change, research proposal, ca. 1963 (Box 53)
    - Highlander Research and Education Center, Inc., 1967-1968 (Box 53)
    - Highlander Research and Education Center, Inc., board of directors, 1964-1968 (Box 53)
    - Hofstra University, draft proposal of special program for high school graduates, 1960 (Box 53)
    - Home economics agents' meeting, 1966 (Box 53)
    - Home Economists Extension Professional Development Program, 1966-1967 (Box 53)
    - Humanistic Institute for Women in Business, Vassar College
      - General, 1956 (Box 54)
      - Newsletter, 1957-1958 (Box 54)
      - Participant reactions, 1956 (Box 54)
      - Questionnaires, 1956 (Box 54)
      - Staff notes, 1956 (Box 54)
    - Hunter College experimental course, CSLEA project #1, 1958-1959 (Box 54)
    - ICUAE
      - Individual memberships, 1966 (Box 54)
      - Journal and occasional papers, constitution and by-laws, 1962-1968 (Box 54)
      - Newsletter, 1961-1966 (Box 55)
    - Illinois Continuing Education Program, rough draft, ca. 1958 (Box 55)
    - Illinois Leaderhip Training Program for Liberal Adult Education, 1959; ca. 1961; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Improvement of Teaching Project, 1952; 1953; 3 folders (Box 55)
    - Independent study program for management development, preliminary proposal, undated (Box 56)
    - Indiana University, survey, 1963 (Box 56)
    - Institute on Urban Education, 1965 (Box 56)
    - Institutional self-studies, surveys, 1960-1961 (Box 56)
    - Integrated curriculum for adults, draft of discussions, 1958 (Box 56)
    - Inter-American Adult Education Committee, 1961 (Box 56)
    - Inter-American Exploratory and Planning Conference, 1961 (Box 56)
    - Interest-aptitude test for adults, inventory, 1958-1962 (Box 56)
    - International Adult Education Conference, 1959 (Box 56)
    - International Center for Study and Learning in Education, 1965 (Box 56)
    - International Conference on University Adult Education (Sagamore Conference), 1960 (Box 56)
    - International Conference on Residential Adult Education, 1954-1960 (Box 56)
    - International Congress on University Adult Education, 1960-1965 (Box 56)
    - Labor Education Committees, 1957-1963 (Box 56)
    - Labor Education (Residential) Program at Indiana University
      - Blue Collar Scholar, 1963-1967 (Box 56)
      - Cupriot Observer, 1963 (Box 56)
      - General, 1957-1966 (Box 56)
      - Supporting papers, 1957-1966 (Box 57)
    - Laboratory college instructional team, 1957 (Box 57)
    - Laboratory college project, 1957-1958; 5 folders (Box 57)
    - Leadership Conferences of CSLEA
      - Second annual, 1954 (Box 57)
      - Fourth annual, 1956 (Box 57)
      - Sixth annual, 1958 (Box 57)
      - Seventh annual, 1959 (Box 57)
      - Eighth annual, 1960 (Box 57)
    - Leading group discussion
      - Notes, ca. 1954 (Box 57)
      - Proposal for a book on the subject, ca. 1957 (Box 57)
      - Training guide III, 1954 (Box 58)
    - League of Women Voters of New York State Workshop on China, miscellaneous papers, ca. 1966 (Box 58)
    - Leisure-time activities of adults, program, 1957-1958 (Box 58)
    - Liberal adult education programs, resume of study of liberal arts colleges' involvement, 1956 (Box 58)
    - Liberal arts for labor at UCLA, 1958 (Box 58)
    - Liberal arts for service clubs, proposal and report, 1960-1961 (Box 58)
    - "Liberal Education and the Practical Man," by George E. Barton, Jr., undated (Box 58)
    - Liberal Education for Adults Faculty Seminar at the University of Oklahoma, 1958 (Box 58)
    - Liberal Education for Management Seminar, 1957
      - Gordon group (Box 58)
      - Miller group (Box 58)
      - Plenary session (Box 58)
    - Liberal Education for Specialists Programs (Operation Micro)
      - DeKalb Project, 1956-1961 (Box 59)
      - Executives, ca. 1959; 2 folders (Box 59)
      - General, 1954-1960 (Box 59)
      - Journalists, 1955-1956 (Box 59)
    - Liberal education in evening college credit programs, ca. 1960
    - Liberal Studies for University Administrators, Second Institute, 1958-1960 (Box 59)
    - Liveright Study on Adult Education, progress reports and drafts, 1965 (Box 59)
    - Liveright trips
      - Africa, 1961 (Box 59)
      - London and UNESCO in Paris, 1963 (Box 59)
    - Metrocenter at Boston University, proposal, 1955 (Box 59)
    - Metrocenter Seminar at Boston University, 1966 (Box 59)
    - Metroplex Assembly, 1957 (Box 59)
    - Metropolitan College, 1965-1967 (Box 59)
    - Metropolitan Education Project
      - 1964 (Box 60)
      - 1965 (Box 60)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 60)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 60)
    - Metropolitan Residential School Board Institute, St. Louis, MO, 1960 (Box 60)
    - Millard Fillmore College, survey, 1955-1958 (Box 60)
    - M.L.S. Degree Program Committee, 1968 (Box 60)
    - National Adult Education Resources Institute and Field Demonstration Centers, proposal, 1961-1967 (Box 60)
    - National Conference on the Urban University and Community Needs, 1954 (Box 60)
    - National Conference on Urban Life, 1962 (Box 60)
    - National Council of Churches Advisory Committee on an Experimental Center for Continuing Education, 1966 (Box 60)
    - National Education Television, 1960-1966 (Box 60)
    - National Seminar on Adult Education Research, 1961-1966 (Box 60)
    - National Seminar on Urban University Problems, proposal, 1963 (Box 60)
    - National University Extension Association
      - Business section, proposals for submission, 1961 (Box 60)
      - Division of correspondence study, meetings and correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box 60)
      - National Liberalizing Conference and Institute programs, 1961 (Box 60)
      - Policy Statement Committee, report, 1961 (Box 60)
      - Reports of various committees, 1951-1968 (Box 61)
    - Nature and purposes of the evening college, 1953 (Box 61)
    - Negro College Program
      - 1959-1963 (Box 61)
      - 1962, 2 folders (Box 61)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 61)
      - 1963 (Box 62)
      - 1964-1967 (Box 62)
      - Undated, 2 folders (Box 62)
    - Negro College Program survey on adult education, questionnaires, undated (Box 62)
    - Neuffer Study of Administrative Practices in AUEC Institutions, 1961 (Box 62)
    - New Center for Adult Education, development meeting, 1967 (Box 62)
    - New England Regional Center for Continuing Education Planning Conference, 1965 (Box 62)
    - Non-credit Programs Workshop, 1954-1956 (Box 62)
    - Northeast Film Center for Children, 1967 (Box 62)
    - Northeastern University, survey, 1957 (Box 62)
    - Northwestern University, survey, 1954-1962 (Box 62)
    - NUEA-AUEC survey for adult education research and evaluation, draft form, undated (Box 63)
    - NUEA-IUS comparative evaluation, proposal, 1963 (Box 63)
    - Observations on developments in higher adult education, 1965 (Box 63)
    - OEF Leadership Institute, field work, 1965; 1968 (Box 63)
    - OWHA meetings, 1968 (Box 63)
    - Ohio State University, survey, 1955-1966 (Box 63)
    - Operation Micro, 1954 (Box 63)
    - Oregon State University, survey, 1957-1959 (Box 63)
    - Oxford Seminar on Adult Education and Race, working paper, 1966 (Box 63)
    - Park Forest College
      - Board of trustees minutes, 1964 (Box 63)
      - Survey, 1964 (Box 63)
    - Pennsylvania State University, survey, 1957-1962 (Box 63)
    - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, survey, 1954 (Box 63)
    - C. W. Post College, Adult Education Program, 1967 (Box 63)
    - Professors of Adult Education, 1960-1966 (Box 63)
    - Project for the Improvement of Curriculum Materials and Teaching Methods, 1953 (Box 63)
    - Queens College, survey, 1955-1961 (Box 63)
    - Resident labor education program at Indiana University, overview and evaluation, 1964 (Box 63)
    - Rochester Institute of Technology, Pageant of the Arts, 1959 (Box 63)
    - Roosevelt University
      - Adult education for women, 1963 (Box 63)
      - Alumni Association proposal to the Fund for Adult Education, 1953 (Box 63)
    - Rutgers University Extension Service, 1960-1963 (Box 63)
    - Second Annual Workshop on Adult Education, proceedings, 1960 (Box 63)
    - Second International Seminar on Workers and Adult Education, 1964 (Box 63)
    - Seminar for Urban University Presidents, 1956 (Box 64)
    - Social roles of the middle-aged person, research proposal, 1954 (Box 64)
    - Social trends: implications for adult education, memorandum, 1955 (Box 64)
    - Social Trends in the U.S., discussion and draft report, 1955 (Box 64)
    - Soft pedagogy study, 1954 (Box 64)
    - South Bend Study on Liberal Adult Education and Cultural Activities, 1964 (Box 64)
    - Special degree programs
      - Boston University
        - Graduate, 1964-1968 (Box 64)
        - Undergraduate, 1965 (Box 64)
      - Evaluation project, undated (Box 64)
      - General
        - 1953-1959 (Box 64)
        - 1960-1966 (Box 64)
      - M.A. especially for adults, 1964 (Box 64)
      - M.A. especially for teachers, 1956-1959 (Box 64)
      - M.A. in general education, 1955-1956 (Box 65)
      - Master of Liberal Studies program for Metropolitan College of Boston University, 1968 (Box 65)
      - Report of conference, 1963 (Box 65)
      - Universities of Oklahoma, Pittsburgh, and Syracuse, 1959 (Box 65)
      - University of Oregon, Portland Extension Center, ca., 1959 (Box 65)
    - Steelworker Institute Program at Pennsylvania State University, 1957-1961 (Box 65)
    - Steelworkers' sabbaticals, 1963-1964 (Box 65)
    - Study of University Extension
      - Institute for University Studies, 1962-1963 (Box 65)
      - St. Louis University, 1954 (Box 65)
      - Syracuse University, 1958-1963 (Box 65)
      - Temple University, undated (Box 65)
      - Tulane University, 1955-1966 (Box 65)
      - University of Akron, 1954 (Box 65)
      - University of British Columbis, 1962 (Box 65)
      - University of California, 1960-1963 (Box 65)
      - University of Chattanooga, 1958 (Box 65)
      - University of Chicago, 1956-1964 (Box 65)
      - University of Cincinnati, 1952-1957 (Box 65)
      - University of Delaware, 1957-1959 (Box 65)
      - University of Denver, 1958 (Box 65)
      - University of Hawaii, 1960-1961 (Box 65)
      - University of London, 1962 (Box 65)
      - University of Minnesota, 1954-1967 (Box 66)
      - University of Mississippi, 1956-1958 (Box 66)
      - University of Missouri, 1968 (Box 66)
      - University of Nebraska, undated (Box 66)
      - University of New Hampshire, ca. 1962 (Box 66)
      - University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, 1958 (Box 66)
      - University of Oklahoma, 1961-1962 (Box 66)
      - University of Omaha, 1958 (Box 66)
      - University of Pennsylvania, 1958 (Box 66)
      - University of Pittsburgh, 1958 (Box 66)
      - University of Rhode Island, 1957 (Box 66)
      - University of Rochester, 1958-1959 (Box 66)
      - University of South Dakota, 1965 (Box 66)
      - University of Texas, ca. 1959 (Box 66)
      - University of Toledo, 1955 (Box 66)
      - University of Utah, undated (Box 66)
      - University of Washington, 1954 (Box 66)
      - University of Wisconsin, 1957-1964 (Box 66)
      - Villanova University, undated (Box 66)
      - Washington University, 1954 (Box 66)
      - Western Reserve University, 1954-1957 (Box 66)
    - Task Force on Urbanism, 1966 (Box 66)
    - Teacher behavior, classroom social structure, student personality and learning, research proposal, 1962 (Box 66)
    - Thirteenth National Conference on Higher Education, report of Session F, 1958 (Box 66)
    - "The Uncommon College," report by A. A. Liveright on Metropolis University, 1966 (Box 66)
    - Undergraduate honors program, proposal, 1959 (Box 67)
    - UNESCO and higher education, report, 1962 (Box 67)
    - UNESCO Regional Seminar in Australia on Adult Education, proposal, 1962 (Box 67)
    - University adult education and manpower utilization, 1960-1961 (Box 67)
    - University adult education in metropolitan New York, analytic survey, ca. 1965 (Box 67)
    - University Adult Education Workshop, Group C, 1960 (Box 67)
    - The university and its urban setting, proposal for a study, ca. 1961 (Box 67)
    - University and the Community: Urban Affairs Conference Toward Improving Local Community Leadership, 1966 (Box 67)
    - University Christian movement, description, 1967 (Box 67)
    - University Council on Education for Public Responsibility, 1962-1967 (Box 67)
    - University of Bridgeport, grant application for experimental study into preparations for part-time faculty, 1959 (Box 67)
    - University of Chicago, research report on differentiating characteristics of students, 1959 (Box 67)
    - University of Chicago, University College, self-study project, ca. 1958 (Box 67)
    - University of Colorado, basic course in labor education for union leaders, 1958-1959 (Box 67)
    - University of Oklahoma, Extension Council, meetings, 1957-1958 (Box 67)
    - University of Wyoming, workshops and programs, 1960 (Box 67)
    - University-PTA Project, report, 1952-1954 (Box 67)
    - Urban Affairs Conference, 1961 (Box 67)
    - Urban Extension, 1961-1963 (Box 67)
    - Washington University Alumni Institute Conference, miscellaneous papers, 1958 (Box 67)
    - Western Reserve University, Women's Association of Cleveland College, analysis of costs, 1958 (Box 67)
    - White Sulphur Springs Conference, summary, 1958 (Box 67)
    - Wingspread Conference on the Arts, various papers, 1962 (Box 68)
    - Women college graduates as agents to increase opportunities for disadvantaged youths, proposal, 1966 (Box 68)
    - Workshop on Accelerating the Preparation of Adult Educators, final report, 1965 (Box 68)
    - Workshop on Adult Education Opportunities in Greater Boston, invited participants, 1967 (Box 68)
    - Workshop on the Purpose of the Evening College, 1953 (Box 68)
    - World Conference on University Adult Education, proposal, 1964 (Box 68)
- Publication files
  - Brochures and announcements, undated (Box 68)
  - Curriculum material
    - The American tradition, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Analytical reading, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Core curriculum for teacher training institutes, 1966 (Box 68)
    - Group living, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Laboratory course in literature, 1951 (Box 68)
    - Laboratory college for adults, 1957; 1958; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - The teaching of adults, ca. 1952 (Box 68)
    - Themes and variations: an invitation to literature, 1952 (Box 68)
    - World politics, 1952 (Box 68)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 68)